windermere.com 2011-06-15

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

The Windermere.com website (Site) is owned and operated by Windermere Services Company (WSC). WSC promises to protect the personal information given to us by visitors to our website. Any information that you give to WSC will be held with the utmost care, and will not be used in any way to which you have not already consented. A more detailed explanation follows.

 **COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**  
Much of the general information on the Site can be accessed without needing to register or log in; we therefore collect no information about you whatsoever when you are accessing these generic areas of our website. To search our database of properties for sale you may select one of three search methods.

 _Anonymous_

: You may elect to remain completely anonymous when you search for properties on the Site. If you select this option we do not collect any personal information from you. This option provides limited access to property information. For example, property addresses may not be disclosed to anonymous users.

 _myWindermere – no agent_

: Users who wish to access more detailed property information and extended searching features (such as the ability to save favorite listings, save searches and have new listings e-mailed to them automatically) may register to create a user account. To create a “myWindermere” account visitors are asked to provide certain contact information. We do not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease this personal information to anyone, except as described in this policy. NOTE: if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of the “myWindermere” features. See below for more details about cookies.

 _myWindermere – with agent_

: Once you have created a “myWindermere” account you may associate your account with a specific Windermere sales associate. When you select an associate to be “My Agent,” the sales associate you selected will be notified that you have done so, and will be provided with your contact information so that he/she may contact you for follow-up. By associating a sales associate as “My Agent,” you consent to be contacted by that associate by phone, even if your phone number appears in any state or national “Do Not Call” registry. The associate may also access details about your property search criteria, and lists of specific properties you have viewed through the Site. 

In selecting an associate as “My Agent” you agree that your use of the Site does not, in and of itself, create an agency relationship between you and the sales associate, or with any Windermere brokerage company. However, further interactions between you and the sales associate (including contacts via e-mail, phone or in person) may result in establishing an agency relationship under the laws of your state, or the state where the agent is located. [Agency Disclosure information](http://www.windermere.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=content.libraryHTMl&contentID=71098) for most states where Windermere operates is available on the Site. NOTE: if your browser settings do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of the “My Agent” features. See below for more details about cookies.

 _Opt-In E-Mail Alerts_

: Once you have registered to create a “myWindermere” account, you will be invited to sign up to receive e-mail alerts about properties that match search criteria you establish. You may change your e-mail alert settings – or opt-out of receiving any future alerts - on the “My Account” page after logging in to “myWindermere.”

_“Request More Information” about a property_. If you have created a “myWindermere” account and associated a sales associate as “My Agent,” then any time you request more information about a property, your request will be routed to the associate you selected as “My Agent.” If you have not selected an associate as “My Agent,” and you request more information about a property listed by a Windermere agent, then your request will be forwarded to the listing agent. If you have not selected an associate as “My Agent” and you request more information about a property listed by a non-Windermere agent, then your request will be forwarded to a service provider selected by WSC to provide service for such requests. The service provider will contact you, and if appropriate refer you to a Windermere agent in your area to assist you further. By clicking “Request More Information,” about a property, you consent to being contacted using the contact information you provide – including phone contact, even if the phone number you provided is listed on any national or state “Do Not Call” registry. Furthermore, by requesting more information about a property you may be offered the opportunity to opt-in to receiving additional, ongoing contacts (by phone and/or e-mail) about other properties meeting your criteria, or about your local real estate market generally. Such ongoing communications will always include instructions for how to unsubscribe from receiving future communications.

_Browser information collected on the website_

: As with many website operators, WSC analyzes our website logs to constantly improve the value of our website to our visitors. We use an external service to provide real-time reporting to us and our authorized agents of browser accesses to our site. This includes the IP addresses used to access our site, page views, unique views, unique visitors, repeat visitors, frequency of visits, and peak-volume traffic periods.

 _Use of cookies_

: We use cookies on our website to provide each visitor with a personalized experience. Cookies are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit our site and that automatically identify your browser to our server whenever you interact with our site. We do link the cookies to your personally identifiable information on our servers, but no personal information is stored in the cookies themselves. We use cookies to track your use of our site, and to authenticate users of the “myWindermere” and “My Agent” features. We do not share cookies with any other site. If you prefer not to allow us to collect cookie information, you can block cookies with your browser as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is sent, or to reject all cookies. However, please note that if you reject some or all cookies, your experience at our Site may not be complete. Specifically, if you do not allow cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of the “myWindermere” or “My Agent” features described above.

 _Other uses of your personal information_

: In addition to using information about you for the specific purposes set out above, from time to time we may also use your personal information to send you news about our organization and new features available on the Site.

**DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION:**  
Except as disclosed in this policy, WSC does not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease personal information collected on our website to any third party. However, information must be released in response to subpoenas or other court orders, and may be released to law enforcement agencies in connection with criminal investigations.

 **DATA QUALITY AND ACCESS:**  
WSC provides you with the opportunity to know about the information that WSC holds about you, together with the ability to correct, amend or delete, as appropriate, any such information that is incomplete or inaccurate. Should you wish to exercise any of these options or should you have any questions or concerns about information that WSC has collected in relation to you, please feel free to contact us by emailing [privacy@windermere.com](mailto:privacy@windermere.com). Specific details on how to correct, change or remove subscription information from our e-mail lists are provided on the “My Account” page of “myWindermere.”

 **ENFORCEMENT:**  
If for any reason you believe that WSC has not adhered to these privacy principles, please notify us by e-mail at [privacy@windermere.com](mailto:privacy@windermere.com), and we will endeavor to review and correct the problem promptly. Please use the words "Privacy Policy" in the Subject line.

 **EXTERNAL LINKS:**  
The Site may provide links to various websites that WSC does not control. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred out of our website and connected to the website of the organization or company that you selected. Even if an affiliation exists between our Site and a third party website, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection practices and procedures. If you visit a website that is linked to our site, you should consult that site's privacy policy before providing any personal information.

 **INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION TRANSFERS**  
Any personally identifiable information that you provide to WSC will be collected and maintained directly on servers located in the United States and Canada. If you are located outside the United States, this means that any information you provide will be transferred abroad. While WSC is committed to providing your information with the highest level of privacy protection, we believe you should know that the general level of protection for personal information in the United States may not be the same as that provided in other countries, including those that belong to the European Economic Area.

 **TERMS AND MODIFICATIONS TO PRIVACY POLICY:**  
By using this website, you signify your agreement to the terms of this privacy policy. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not disclose any personal information through the Site. WSC may modify this privacy policy at any time at its discretion and modifications are effective upon being posted on the Site. You are responsible for reviewing this privacy policy periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it.

 **CONTACTING WSC ABOUT PRIVACY:**  
If you have any questions or concerns regarding privacy on the Site, please contact us at [privacy@windermere.com.](mailto:privacy@windermere.com)

This policy was last updated on June 25, 2007
